<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog</id>
    <title>Charles Ancheta Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Charles Ancheta Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://cbebe.github.io/v2/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Log: Boboman - Day 4]]></title>
        <id>dev-log/boboman/day4</id>
        <link href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog/dev-log/boboman/day4"/>
        <updated>2022-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I feel like the hardest part of writing this game would be the enemy logic. That's why I'm putting it off for as long as]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I feel like the hardest part of writing this game would be the enemy logic. That's why I'm putting it off for as long as
possible! Today I implemented map generation, randomly placing boxes sufficiently far enough from players.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="/v2/assets/images/multiplayer-2f7e2c7ce9f6173738d3574d5e638d9e.webp" width="1366" height="768" class="img_Yyx3"></p><p>I also added controls for other players, which reminded me of my local multiplayer experience with Boxhead. I miss
having multiple people on play a single keyboard. These days it would be awkward to play that way.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Ancheta</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/cbebe</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="dev-log" term="dev-log"/>
        <category label="love" term="love"/>
        <category label="lua" term="lua"/>
        <category label="multiplayer" term="multiplayer"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Log: Boboman - Day 3]]></title>
        <id>dev-log/boboman/day3</id>
        <link href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog/dev-log/boboman/day3"/>
        <updated>2022-07-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Feeling good today. I got to fix the collision bug that was happening yesterday. It actually had to do with the]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Feeling good today. I got to fix the collision bug that was happening yesterday. It actually had to do with the
collision lifecycle, so to make the player detectable, I decoupled the check from the lifecycle of the bomb. Because of
this, I could revert the player's bomb timer to normal. Moving away from a project and letting your brain sit on a
problem for a while really does wonders.</p><p>I also created an enemy entity based off the player asset and make that and the box entities destructible by explosions.
I thought I lost my commit progress on it after mashing a few keys on <code>lazygit</code>, but I got it back after a <code>git reflog</code>
and <code>git cherry-pick</code> combo.</p><p>Overall, I'm making pretty good progress, and shaping the game more by adding stuff to the TODO.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Ancheta</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/cbebe</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="dev-log" term="dev-log"/>
        <category label="love" term="love"/>
        <category label="lua" term="lua"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Log: Boboman - Day 2]]></title>
        <id>dev-log/boboman/day2</id>
        <link href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog/dev-log/boboman/day2"/>
        <updated>2022-07-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MAJOR BUG ALERT!!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>MAJOR BUG ALERT!!</p><p>Apparently my collision logic for the bombs weren't going to hold up. Every time a bomb explodes, there is a small time
window where you can place a bomb and the bomb would not recognize the player, making it a "not new" bomb. Because of
that, the player gets pushed off right away and could end up in the weirdest of places.</p><p>After hours of debugging I couldn't really solve it because of how the collision library orders the entity updates. I
didn't feel like giving up for today, though, and making no progress. I simply created a deployment script to deploy the
game to <a href="https://cbebe.github.io/boboman/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub pages</a> and fixed the player update logic so it at least doesn't end up
outside of the map. Still a pretty good day even if I didn't make as much progress as I wanted.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Ancheta</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/cbebe</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="dev-log" term="dev-log"/>
        <category label="love" term="love"/>
        <category label="lua" term="lua"/>
        <category label="gh-pages" term="gh-pages"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Log: Boboman - Day 1]]></title>
        <id>dev-log/boboman/day1</id>
        <link href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog/dev-log/boboman/day1"/>
        <updated>2022-07-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently, I've been heavily configuring my text editor, Neovim, which means that I've been writing a lot of Lua. I do]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I've been heavily configuring my text editor, Neovim, which means that I've been writing a lot of Lua. I do
find it enjoyable, even without having any tooling initially, so I wanted to give game development and
<a href="https://love2d.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Love2D</a> a try. I just finished
<a href="https://www.sheepolution.com/learn/book/contents" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sheepolution's How to LÖVE</a> book on Love2D, and felt prepared to make
my first game from scratch. As per Jherzey's request, I'm creating a Bomberman clone.</p><p>I tried looking for libraries that might be useful at first, such as the ones used in
<a href="https://github.com/bakpakin/CommandoKibbles" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Commando Kibbles</a>. I wanted to set up an Entity-Component system and all
those other fancy game dev stuff I've been hearing about. However, I realized that I should only use the ones that I
don't feel like re-writing. After all, the prerequisite to writing good code is writing bad code. In the end, <em>Boboman</em>
seems like a fitting title, because I do feel dumb writing this game.</p><p>Anyway, here's what it looks like now. You can walk around, place bombs, and those bombs explode after a set amount of
time, leaving a trail of explosion. The explosions don't go past the walls.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Boboman Day 1 demo" src="/v2/assets/images/boboman-81f5324a09b21c5973c71e5ad3c65132.gif" width="800" height="630" class="img_Yyx3"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Ancheta</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/cbebe</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="dev-log" term="dev-log"/>
        <category label="love" term="love"/>
        <category label="lua" term="lua"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bye bye Netlify]]></title>
        <id>bye-bye-netlify</id>
        <link href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog/bye-bye-netlify"/>
        <updated>2022-06-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was short trial, but GitHub Pages just works better for me.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was short trial, but GitHub Pages just works better for me.</p><p>A couple of weeks ago, I moved my website from GitHub Pages to Netlify, hoping for a better development and production
experience. I didn't really have a need to move just yet, but I wanted to see what the buzz about Netlify was about. So
I spent a few hours setting it up and pointing my domain to the Netlify app.</p><p>It was working just fine at first, until I started making updates. The page would just load indefinitely and I would
have to visit <code>cbebe.netlify.app</code> first before <code>charlesancheta.com</code> would behave properly. I've had a few embarrassing
moments showing my website to people for a couple times and it refusing to load.</p><p>Another annoying was that every pull request and push to the master branch would trigger a build, even if none of the
pages were modified. Netlify only provides a limited about of build time every month, so I found myself cancelling more
builds in the Netlify dashboard more often than I manually deployed a build using the command line. This could be nice
if other people were contributing to this repo, but since this is a personal website, I find that unlikely.</p><p>Realizing these, I moved back to GitHub Pages and manually deploying with the CLI. Maybe in the future where I would
have to actually launch a production-level static website that I would revisit Netlify, but for now, I'll stick with my
current workflow.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Ancheta</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/cbebe</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="netlify" term="netlify"/>
        <category label="hosting" term="hosting"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friendship Ended with TypeScript, now Go is My Best Friend]]></title>
        <id>/2022/06/07/friendship-ended</id>
        <link href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog/2022/06/07/friendship-ended"/>
        <updated>2022-06-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Friendship ended]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Friendship ended" src="/v2/assets/images/friendship-ended-81753b98ed56ffb6ff2b0c00e7f78cf0.webp" width="680" height="510" class="img_Yyx3"></p><p>No blog post here, just a quick edit I made in GIMP.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Ancheta</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/cbebe</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="dev" term="dev"/>
        <category label="go" term="go"/>
        <category label="typescript" term="typescript"/>
        <category label="backend" term="backend"/>
        <category label="meme" term="meme"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TIL: My actual height]]></title>
        <id>til/my-actual-height</id>
        <link href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog/til/my-actual-height"/>
        <updated>2022-05-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I learned what my actual height was (at least at the time of writing). For a few years now I've always kind of]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I learned what my actual height was (at least at the time of writing). For a few years now I've always kind of
just stuck with 170 cm because that's what was in my driver's license when I got it 5 years ago (I really need to pass
the road test this year). I'm not even sure if that was right at the time.</p><p>So, I took a couple of IKEA measuring tapes (courtesy of Jherzey), put them together on a post in our basement, got a
square ruler (triangular? (<!-- -->*<!-- -->sigh<!-- -->*<!-- -->...
<a href="https://philnews.ph/2021/06/10/eskwala-in-english-translate-eskwala-in-english/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>eskwala</em></a>)) and measured my height.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A square measuring my height at 173 cm" src="/v2/assets/images/173cm-878f5d7a25cfd68eb8a8389497e78c23.webp" width="1536" height="2048" class="img_Yyx3"></p><p>So I guess I grew 3 cm in those 5 years? I still haven't caught up to my dad's peak height (176 cm), but he's a bit
shorter now that he's older, so it's okay. My hair can add at least 2 inches 😂.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Ancheta</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/cbebe</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="til" term="til"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome!]]></title>
        <id>welcome</id>
        <link href="https://cbebe.github.io/v2/blog/welcome"/>
        <updated>2022-05-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to my website! I am Charles, a Computer Engineering Student working as a Full Stack Web Developer.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my website! I am Charles, a Computer Engineering Student working as a Full Stack Web Developer.</p><p>For someone who spends a lot of time typing in front of a computer, I write down very little of my thoughts. Most stuff
that I come back to for memories are just old code and old pictures, and this should hopefully change that.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Ancheta</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/cbebe</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="welcome" term="welcome"/>
        <category label="first" term="first"/>
    </entry>
</feed>